Guide to the WPP Group records, 1986-2015 and undated RL.11178
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WPP Group records
1986-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WPP Group plc
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11178
3.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1971 as a manufacturer of shopping baskets; converted into a holdling company in 1985 and grew to become one of the largest advertising and communications conglomerates in the world.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
WPP plc (Wire and Plastic Products) founded 1971 as a manufacturer of wire shopping baskets and carts. Martin Sorrell acquired a controlling interest in 1985 and renamed it WPP Group. Sorrell became CEO. Major acquisitions of advertising agencies: J. Walter Thompson 1987; Ogilvy Group 1989; Young & Rubicam 2000; Grey Group 2005.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The WPP Group records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1998-2015.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Don Johnston papers; J. Walter Thompson Company Publications; Kenneth Roman papers; Wunderman Archives.
Collection Overview
Spans 1986-2015 and includes annual reports, financial statements, correspondence, artifacts, newsletters and other publications and printed materials. Includes materials pertaining to the acquisition of the Ogilvy Group (formerly Ogilvy & Mather). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; WPP Group plc; J. Walter Thompson Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Annual reports, 1986-1995; 7 folders (Box 1)
- Annual reports, 1996-2003; 4 folders (Box 2)
- Articles, 1986-2013 (Box 2)
- Atticus Awards, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Center for Research and Development--Options and Opportunities for Consumer Businesses: Advertising in a Recession, 1990 (Box 3)
- Corporate Responsibility Report, 2006-2008 (Box 3)
- Directories, 1987-1995; 2 folders (Box 3)
- Financial reports, 1995-1999 (Box 3)
- Financial reviews, 1987 (Box 3)
- Group Navigator, 1996-2006 (Box 3)
- Interim reports, 1987-2001 (Box 3)
- Marketing Fellowship program, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
- Martin Sorrell speech: Beans and Pearls, 1996 (Box 4)
- Newsletter--Network WPP, 1989-1996 (Box 4)
- North American Client Index, undated (Box 4)
- Ogilvy acquisition, 1989 (Box 4)
- Promotional merchandise: postcards, t-shirt designs, undated (Box 4)
- Research International--Innovation in Advertising Research, 1995 (Box 4)
- Samuel Montagu--Capital restructuring proposal, 1992 (Box 4)
- Shareholder materials, 1988-1999 (Box 4)
- The Catalog: Inventory of WPP Innovations that Can Help Group Companies Win, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
- WPP: 30 Years of Communications Service, 2015 (Box 4)
- WPP: Partnership in Practice, 1997 (Box 4)
- WPP Retail Seminar, 1996 (Box 4)
- WPPed Cream, 2014 (Box 4)
- Newsletter--The Wire, 1997-2005 (Box 5)
- Promotional merchandise: baseball cap, t-shirts, undated (Box 5)
- The World of WPP, 1989 (Box 5)
- WPPed Cream, 2007-2008 (Box 5)